

# **ROLANDAS SEPUTIS**

## PERSONAL INFO



**ADDRESS** 

Vilnius, Dituvos 19, LT06283



E-MAIL

vi.kvadrantas@gmail.com



PHONE

8 618 29966



### **LANGUAGES**

LITHUANIAN •••••
ENGLISH ••••
RUSSIAN

## **DESIRED POSITION**

I am switching from Senior IT Engineer position to Junior Software Engineer as a first step approach. I've been working in IT sector as an engineer for 17 years and I am willing to have new challenges, and the developer position was always in my dreams, which I was ignoring until now. To make my transition smoother I am attending JavaScript 5.5 month full time courses which will be finished at the end of November. I am studying JavaScript, Node.js HTML/CSS and React, so my primary interest is JavaScript Frontend or Full stack junior developer position



## EDUCATION

2000 - 2004 ENGINEERING INFORMATICS, BACHELOR'S DEGREE

VILNIUS GEDIMINAS TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY

Domanto Matulaviciaus vardine stipendija

1988 - 2000 SECONDARY EDUCATION

SILUTE 4-TH SECONDARY SCHOOL



## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2019 - 2020

#### **VISMA**

#### IT ENGINEER FOR MIGRATION PROJECT

- Hired for fixed term project- to migrate digital signature online portal/services.
- Investigation of existing production, development, demo and test
- Creating new highly available & load balanced design both for frontend WEB and backend SQL infrastructure
- Installing, configuring and building new infrastructure
- Migrating old environment to new
- Configuring backups and monitoring for new servers
- Documenting new environment

Windows; Windows NLB; WEB Farm; MS SQL Clustering (Always On); RabbitMQ Clustering; Octopus; Anturis;

2015 - 2019

### **BARCLAYS**

### SENIOUR 3-RD LINE MESSAGING ENGINEER

- Working in large multi-international organization with complex messaging environment consisting of hundreds of CAS/HUB, mailbox and other servers in a highly available and load balanced environment spread among different geographic regions and consisting of 250K mailboxes.
- Updating servers
- Implementing BAU changes
- Solving 3-rd line incidents and requests
- Managing Exchange backups
- Managing journaling & archiving servers
- Managing antivirus & antispam protection
   Installing additional MS Exchange servers
- Participating in migration from Exchange 2007 to 2013

## **TECHNOLOGIES** I WORK WITH

































MAILMARSHAL







MS Exchange 2007/2010/2013 MailMarshal Enterprise Vault MS DPM Symantec and Forefront protection

2011 - 2015

## **HOSTEX / BDC /TEO**

### SENIOR IT ADMINISTRATOR (3-RD LINE SUPPORT)

- Installing and configuring virtual and physical servers for new clientsConfiguring monitoring & alerting for servers
- Configuring backups jobs
- Updating OS & software
- Fixing issues & alerts
- Building clusters, load balancing for highly available environments
- Building and managing WEB hosting servers
- Solving client incidents
- Maintaining hundreds of servers to keep them up & running

MS Exchange 2007/2010/2013 Windows 2003/2008/2012 Active Directory / DNS / DHCP / WEB IIS / WSUS / Terminal Servers VMware / Hyper-V / Virtuozzo WEB Hosting Plesk VEEAM / Acronis / MS DPM Nagios / SCOM / Cactis

2005 - 2011

## STATE LABOUR INSPECTORATE

### SENIOR IT INGINEER

- Managing all IT infrastructure

Windows NT/2003/2008 / AD / DNS / DHCP MDaemon Mail Server MS SQL / My SQL Firewal administration Antispam server Panda GateDefender Web Server (IIS) / Aplication Server / File server WEB CMS Smartweb Antivirus servers: Symantec, Panda



## TRAININGS & CERTIFICATION

### **CERTIFICATES GAINED**

### JAVASCRIPT / NODE.JS / HTML / CSS /REACT

Baltic Institute of Technology - Javascript, Node.js, React and HTML/CSS Studies. (5.5 month duration full time course).

Udemy - The Complete JavaScript Course 2021: From Zero To Expert!

Udemy - Build Responsive Real-World Websites With HTML And CSS.

### **MICROSOFT**

Microsoft Certified Azure Administrator Associate MCTS: Microsoft Exchange Server 2010, Configuration MCTS: Windows Server® 2008 Active Directory, Configuration Microsoft® Certified Technology Specialist (MCTS) MCTS: Windows Server® 2008 Network Infrastructure, Configuration MCITP: Server Administrator on Windows Server® 2008 Microsoft® Certified IT Professional (MCITP) MCTS: Windows Server® 2008 Applications Infrastructure, Configuration

MCTS: SQL Server® 2008, Implementation and Maintenance

**VMware** 

VMware Certified Professional on vSphere 5